Rabelani Neluheni CA(SA)

Crossberry Central Security Estate Diagonal St, Grand Central Midrand 1685

Cell: +2765 892 0000 / +2773 659 8177 **Email:** neluhenirabelani@gmail.com

Curriculum Vitae

Professional Profile

Experienced auditor with over 6 years of experience in public practice across various industries and accounting standards. This has solidified my technical financial reporting knowledge, as well as my knowledge on South African tax, corporate governance, and compliance. Fully qualified Chartered Accountant registered with the South African Institute of Chartered Accountants (SAICA) as a Chartered Accountant South Africa (CA(SA)).

Currently working for Makosi Consulting a company based in New York City as an advance senior audit consultant. Completed articles at Deloitte South Africa. During my articles, was involved in audits of financial statements in numerous different sectors and industries including aviation, manufacturing, automotive, mining, non-food retail, healthcare, Labour Recruitment and Provision of Staff, NPOs and public sector (government departments and municipalities).

Major clients include ASSORE Ltd, South African Airways (SAA) Edcon Holdings Ltd; Adcorp Holding Limited; Volvo Group Southern Africa Proprietary Limited; Chipkins Puratos (Pty) Ltd and National Home Builders Registration Council amongst others.

Motivated and hard-working individual who wants to expand the knowledge and skills obtained thus far. Believes in life-long learning. Passionate about creating valuable relationships with people and I enjoy working with and managing a team. I believe that leadership requires empathy, compassion, and kindness, and I pride myself on my interpersonal skills.

Educational Details, Skills and Hobbies

,	Skills aria riobbies		
Education		University of Limpopo 2017 Post Graduate Diploma in Accountancy/CTA University of Limpopo 2013-2016 Bachelor of Accounting Sciences	
		Thohoyandou Secondary School 2012 National Senior Certificate	
Professional Memberships	Qualifications 8		
Skills		 Leadership skills Analytical thinking skills Teamwork skills Organisational skills Communication skills Ability to work under pressure Advanced Microsoft Excel and Word skills 	

Career Summary

	Makosi Consulting Advanced Audit Senior / 1st Year Manager
November 2021 to present	Financial Accountant (Group reporting & Analysis) at ASSORE Ltd (Mining company), responsibilities including: • Manage all accounting transactions • Prepare budget forecasts • Preparation of management accounts

- Prepare cashflows
- Handle monthly, quarterly and annual closings
- Reconcile accounts payable and receivable
- Ensure timely bank payments
- Compute taxes and prepare tax returns
- Manage balance sheets and profit/loss statements
- Reinforce financial data confidentiality and conduct database backups when necessary
- Comply with financial policies and regulations

Assistant Manager at **Auditor General South Africa**, responsible for executions and completion of audit for the South African Airways (SAA) audit including:

- Planning and assigning work to junior stuff members
- Review of working paper
- Managing and coaching team members
- Testing consolidations of AFS

Senior audit consultant for **Earnest & Young United State and Europe**, responsible for the execution and completion of audit including:

- Detail review of work papers prepared by junior staff members.
- Working in and managing projects and teams to meet audit deadlines.
- Mentor team members and peers with active training, including technical training, administrative, and interpersonal soft skills.

Deloitte South Africa Audit Senior

- Responsible for the execution and completion of audit and review engagements in various different industries including manufacturing, automotive, mining, non-food retail, healthcare and public sector (government departments).
- Perform and review audit procedures over balance sheet and income statement accounts for clients ranging from start up to over 23 billion in revenue.
- Act as main point of contact between the team, client contacts and managers to conveys status, open items, and identified issues both verbally and in writing.
- Working in and managing projects and teams to meet audit deadlines.
- Mentor team members and peers with active training, including technical training, administrative, and interpersonal soft skills.
- Supervision of up to 8 staff on an audit
- Overseeing the scope, strategy, execution and conclusion sections of the audit to meet stringent audit deadlines.
- Drafting of correcting accounting journal entries
- Scheduled the kick-off meetings for the audit together with the taking stock meetings required for the audit.
- Drafted the audit opinion for review by the audit manager and partner.
- Drafting engagement letters for review by the audit manager and partner.
- Drafting the management representation letter for review by manager and partner.
- Assessment of business and audit risks at assertion and financial statement levels. Performing analytic reviews on the financial statements including ratio analyses such as return of capital employed and liquidity ratios to identify trends or areas of concern.
- Calculating and documenting materiality based on the audit firm guidelines and nature of the company and industry.
- Mentoring and reviewing the work of junior trainees as an audit senior.
- Conducting risk assessments and determining the materiality for engagements.

August 2018 - October 2021

	 Assessment of statement of cash flows Budget and forecast analysis for engagements based on the audit fee agreed Evaluate the entity's ability to continue as a going concern Evaluate management's budget and future cash flow assessment Evaluating compliance with International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS) and other relevant statutory requirements including Companies Act, Income Tax Act and Value Added Tax Act Review of Financial Statements in accordance with International Financial Reporting Standards and the requirements of the Companies Act. Review of current and deferred tax calculations as well as review of VAT and VAT returns Assessment of fraud within a client in compliance with the International Auditing Standards (ISA 240) Auditing complex sections such as IFRS 9 Fina, IFRS 16 Leases and IFRS 15 Revenue. Preparing audit planning reports to be presented to management. Reviewing the group consolidation prepared by the client including consolidation journals. Preparing group instructions for component auditors. Scoping of account balances and assertions to be tested during the audit engagement based on both risks of material misstatements identified and materiality. Assessing the impact of changes to accounting standards on the entity's financial statements Liaising with experts and specialists (including but not limited to IT, internal audit and valuation specialists Review of significant accounts such as, Revenue, PPE, Receivables, Payables, Operating Expense and Taxation by ensuring the validity, accuracy and completeness. Confirming the documented process flow with the client. Performing test of controls in accordance with the International Standard on Auditing (ISA) 	
	KPMG South Africa	
	Trainee Accountant	
	Involved in statutory audits and advisory of clients in the public sector	
January 2018 – August 2018	(government departments and municipalities)	

ianuary 2018 – August 2018

- Involved in statutory audits and advisory of clients in the public sector (government departments and municipalities)
- Execution of audits
- Execution of advisory projects

References

Name	Jessica Makua	Mamello Thebe	Nthabiseng Ndima
Job Title	Engagement Manager	Manager	Manager
Company	Makosi	Auditor General South Africa	Deloitte
Email	Jessica.Makua@makosi.com	mamellot@agsa.co.za	
Phone number	+27(0)71 683 3355	+27(0)73 633 0972	+27(0)812101723